# **Michael Rago**

💌 michael.rago@gmail.com 💡 Atlantic City, NJ 🛚 in LinkedIn 🔭 michaelrago.com

# **Summary**

I am a software engineer based in New Jersey. I'm the creator of TextSomebody , an SMS app built with Ruby on Rails, and the co-creator of Able, an A/B testing framework for Jamstack applications. I have multiple years of experience in both the Ruby and JavaScript ecosystems.

# **Professional Experience**

# **Creator,** *TextSomebody* □

11/2022 - present

- Built web app for sharing SMS conversations using Rails 7, PostgreSQL and Redis
- Enabled websocket communication to update UI in real-time using ActionCable
- Integrated Rails app with Twilio's Programmable SMS API using Twilio-ruby gem and wrapper classes
- Configured endpoint and controller to utilize Twilio API's webhook feature
- Inserted custom JavaScript into Asset Pipeline for enhanced user experience
- Designed UI using Bootstrap5
- · Wrote text and created graphics for project website

# **Co-Creator/Software Engineer,** *Able* □

08/2021 - 02/2022

- Co-created Able, an A/B testing framework for Jamstack applications
- Wrote Cloudflare Worker script to inspect incoming HTTP requests and handle according to project requirements
- Automated provisioning and deployment using Node.js, Cloudflare API and AWS SDK/CDK
- · Authored case study and website

## Full Stack Web Developer, Self-Employed

01/2020 - 07/2021

- Created Request Bin, a utility for inspecting HTTP requests using JavaScript and PostgreSQL
- Built Todos, a task management application built with Node.js, Handlebars, HTML and CSS

**Editor,** Faceted Press 07/2014 - 12/2020

- Worked closely with principal author to edit popular LandOf 

  Z series of children's books
- Represented company at sales and marketing events

# Legal Administrative Specialist, Social Security Administration

08/2008 - 08/2011

- Adjusted benefit rates in accordance with the Social Security Act
- Corresponded with beneficiaries by phone and mail regarding benefit rates and adjustments

## **Programmer Analyst, UMDNJ**

08/2001 - 09/2004

- Supported users of Oracle Forms application on three campuses health professions university
- Designed and maintained processes and reports using Visual Basic and SQL.
- Analyzed and troubleshot all aspects of student information systems

#### **Education**

# **Bachelor of Arts, Rutgers University**

09/1993 – 05/1997 | New Brunswick, NJ

### Skills

Languages (JavaScript, Ruby, Golang, HTML, CSS, SQL),

Frameworks (Rails, Express, React (Redux, Router), Sinatra, Bootstrap),

Cloud (Cloudflare Workers, Docker, Heroku, AWS SDK, AWS CDK, EC2, RDS, ALB),

Technologies (Node.js, Git, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Jest, EJS, ERB, NGINX, RESTful APIs)